领导人民群众进行了艰苦卓绝的革命斗争
Lead the people to the arduous revolutionary struggle
从创建革命根据地
From create revolutionary base
走农村包围城市武装夺取政权的道路
The road of armed seizing power of surrounding the cities from the countryside
到红军二万五千里的长征
The red army long march of twenty-five thousand li
到开展敌后抗日斗争
To carry out behind the anti-japanese struggle
取得抗日战争到最后取得解放战争的胜利
The war of resistance against Japan to finally obtain the liberation war victory
中国共产党领导人民经过二十八年艰苦卓绝的斗争
The communist party of China leads the people after 28 years of arduous struggle
推翻了帝国主义封建主义官僚资本主义三座大山
Overthrow imperialism, feudalism bureaucratic capitalism three mountain
建立了中华人民共和国
The People's Republic of China was established
中国人民从此站起来了The Chinese people have stood up from now on